[music]
[Instructor] All right. Cool.
We've got some really good Effects
happening right now. If we press Play,
you can see
you can see that we have dirt that comes
out when the Player runs.
And then they jump,
the dirt stops.
They land, the dirt starts again.
And then when they run
into one of the barriers,
a huge puff of smoke comes out.
Now to really finish out this game,
and give it that nice last
bit of polish that it needs,
we're actually going to add
"Sounds," and some "Music."
What we're going to do is
if you go to your "Main Camera."
Now on your Main Camera,
there is a very interesting
Component on the Camera
called an "Audio Listener."
Much like you need ears
to hear in the real world,
or on a camera you need
a microphone,
in Unity, you need to add
an Audio Listener
to be able to hear sounds
in the environment.
Now another thing that we
can to our Main Camera,
if we go to "Add Component,"
if I actually type in "Audio,"
you see there's all these options.
And in fact, we can actually
add in an "Audio Source."
Our Audio Source is actually
where we can get Audio
like clips of Music
or Sound Effects to actually play.
We're going to go
into our Library again,
of our course.
In our "Course Library," you should
actually see a sound Folder.
So if we expand that...
Now we have two options
for Music or Sound Effects.
In this case, we're going to add
some Music.
And there's 3 different
options that we can Play from.
You can see when you click
on one of the Effects,
if we press Play
in our little preview,
[cool game music]
That beat's really cool.
Let's see if we do the second one.
[dark game music]
That one's a little...
a little darker themed.
We're not in a nighttime course,
but that would be really cool.
Or our last one...
[happy game music]
This one definitely screams
happy forest.
We're actually going to use
this Sound Effect,
and we're going to go
to our Main Camera.
I believe it was that
third clip of music.
We'll actually drag
this to our "Audio Source."
Now when we press Play,
we should just hear some music
playing in the background.
[happy game music]
Not bad. Sounds really good.
Now one thing we want
to make sure is
it seemed like a pretty short
clip itself.
It's like 48 seconds.
If the Player makes it that far,
then the music will just end
so we definitely don't
want that to happen.
If we go to the Main Camera,
we can actually just "Loop."
And then it was a little bit loud
so we'll just turn it down maybe to...
Do like... 0.6 is probably fine.
So 60%.
So now when we Play our game,
again, we'll hear
the Music one more time.
It should be a bit quieter.
[happy game music]
Not bad. Just set it down
a little bit
so that way when
we add Sound Effects,
we'll be able to hear
the Sound Effects over the Music.
Otherwise,
the music might be too loud.
[happy game music]
Cool. With that,
what you're going to do
is you're going to go
to your Main Camera.
You're going to Add a Component
for an Audio Source.
And then you're going to go
into the Assets Folder,
go to the Course Library.
Under Course Library,
go to Sound.
Under Sound, we'll go
into the Music Folder.
You can pick one of
the three bits of music
that you really like.
And then,
in our Main Camera,
just make sure that you click
and drag whichever
Music you want
into the Audio Source.
And then make sure that you click Loop,
and then you can adjust the Volume
to be however loud or quiet
that you want.
Now it's your turn.
[music]